<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on 龚成明@DERI</title>
    <link>https://gongchm.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on 龚成明@DERI</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 龚成明</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/post/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>应用软件开发人员的软件素养</title>
      <link>https://gongchm.github.io/post/software-ability/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gongchm.github.io/post/software-ability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“软件定义一切”、“软件创造价值”，非计算机软件专业出身的其他专业人员投身应用软件开发后，充分发挥自己掌握的所在领域知识和洞见的价值离不开通过实现优秀的软件来解决领域的问题，具备良好的计算机专业的素养能使自己发挥领域能力如虎添翼。花适当的精力来提升自己的软件素养是非常有必要也是值得的。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;应用软件研发人员提升软件素养始终要注意的是不能走向另外一个极端，即过多的关注了软件，而忽视不断提升对自身领域问题的分析能力，不断提升自己设计或寻找以及实现或集成最合适的算法来解决领域问题的能力，不然自己真正的武功就会偏废了。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;应用软件研发人员提升软件素养的基本出发点是要理解软件的特点。实现的软件用于解决我们问题中的正常情形所做的工作所化的工作可能占不到一半，要想到自己实现的软件可能会运行几年甚至几十年，开始编写代码的时候就要想到，还要把大量的精力花在如何适应和容错异常情形，花在如何让别人看懂和修改自己的代码上，如何适应功能的扩展，如何适应问题规模的增长。从编写产品代码的第一天起，头脑里面就要有这些意识。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;应用软件研发人员提升软件素养的更高一点的要求是能够用专业的工具和专业的思路来提升软件开发的效率和质量。其中非常基础也非常重要的是要学会使用版本管理工具，特别是现在已经有了能够支持分布式版本管理的Git和Hg，对于有效控制团队协作软件开发过程是非常有效的工具。其次，是要理解编码构建之外的大量工作的价值，特别是设计和测试的价值，希望高级别的应用软件开发人员花在编码构建上的时间最多不要超过50%。第三，是要避免自己重新或从头造轮子，平台方面要多利用公用组件，学会给平台提需求，应用方面要多复用已有的好的组建；目前的软件生态环境下，大量的开源软件是一个巨大的宝库，除了去使用，还可以积极的去参与到一些开源项目中去。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;最后一点，应用软件研发人员也要关注新技术。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;今天专题交流的内容为自动化系统的演化——面向“网站即软件”和通信、数据封装新技术在数据采集中的应用。希望应用人员在理解这些新技术以后继续专注于领域问题的解决。&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>在首届非洲智能电网论坛闭幕式上的致辞</title>
      <link>https://gongchm.github.io/post/cote-divoire/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2014 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gongchm.github.io/post/cote-divoire/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;5月16日中午，首届非洲智能电网论坛主要议程已经结束，主办方到餐厅找到了中国国家电网公司代表团，提出希望邀请SGCC在下午的闭幕式上致辞。因几位领导的行程已定，我被指派在下午的闭幕式上代表国网致辞。公司副总工程师王益民先生对如何致辞作了认真细致的交待，中午花一个多小时完成致辞初稿，驻非办领导任远帮助进行了修改。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fri, May 16, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abidjan, Cote d’ivoire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good afternoon, Dear&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Adama Toungara, Minister of Oil and Energy,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Dominique Kakou, Director General of CIE,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Frans Vreeswijk, Secretary Generalof IEC,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Claude Kutwa, AFSEC President,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good afternoon, Ladies and Gentlemen,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On behalf of the State Grid Corporation of China, on behalf of Madem Chen Yueming, the Executive Vice President of SGCC and the head of SGCC delegation, I’d first express the warmest congratulations on the success of the first Africa Smart Grid Forum. During this forum, SGCC shared the ideas, practice and achievements on the design and implementation of the smart grid in China. Experts from different countries and organizations gave us positive feedback and valuable comments and also their specific ideas and experience sharing on this forum are quite helpful to us. We have benefited a lot from the forum and we regard this forum as a high-level and valuable event for the electricity professions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The practice of smart grid started in China from only several years ago, but the rapid and significant progress has been achieved. One of the most favorable factors for the progress is that China is a developing country and the grid there is also under developing. We could systematically plan the development of smart grid without too many constraints of traditional ways. The second favorable factor is that the power system of State Grid is quite large. We could test different ideas in different areas at the same time and then apply the successful results to the whole grid later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Africa is the land of hope. Many Africa countries and grids are rapidly developing and facing many challenges as China once faced. When facing the future progress, Africa colleagues are wisely considering the journey of smart grid. It will definitely be a hopeful while challenging journey. SGCC are willing to share our experience continuously, deal with the challenges together and explore the new innovative solutions bravely. We have established our Africa office based in South Africa, aiming to enhance the exchange and cooperation in Africa. Let’s join our hands for wider and deeper cooperation in the development of smart grid in Africa and contribute the most for the takeoff of Africa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Congratulate the success of the forum again. Welcome you to come to China and visit SGCC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>通过了IEEE Computer Society的CSDP认证</title>
      <link>https://gongchm.github.io/post/csdp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gongchm.github.io/post/csdp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;5月出版的IEEE Computer杂志在Computer Society Connection专栏公布了最新通过CSDP认证的名单，很荣幸我名列其中，自己努力尝试的目标达成了。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;自己的专业教育背景和从事的工作是电气工程，但是提供的产品和服务都是软件方面的，尽管平时不断在学习软件方面的知识，但是一直觉得缺少系统的训练和检验。正好看到IEEE计算机协会开展软件工程的认证，决定参照这一认证的要求系统地学习软件工程的理论，学完了以后报名参加了IEEE的考试。考试时又有机会回了趟南大母校，考试的方式是和外语考试类似的机考，英文试卷。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;考试后就等着结果，最终等到了通过的消息，对自己来说，也更有信心去从事软件领域的工作。我也会向其他同事朋友推荐这一认证考试。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;一起公布通过这批认证的美国人有87位，中国人有3位，印度人有7位，其他国家的有21位。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CSDP认证借鉴了PMP认证的方式，发布了Software Engineering Body of Knowledge(SWBOK)，以此知识体系作为认证的基础。SWBOK涵盖软件需求、软件设计、软件构造、软件测试、软件维护、软件配置管理、软件工程管理、软件工程过程、软件工程工具和方法、软件质量共十个知识领域，其中通过CSDP认证可被认为达到proficiency of standard software development practices的程度。稍低一个级别的认证是CSDA。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Computer Society Connection的原文可以从&lt;a href=&#34;http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?tp=&amp;amp;arnumber=5472895&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;IEEE Xplore&lt;/a&gt;上下载到。&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
