<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on 龚成明@DERI</title>
    <link>https://gongchm.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on 龚成明@DERI</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 龚成明</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/post/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>在首届非洲智能电网论坛闭幕式上的致辞</title>
      <link>https://gongchm.github.io/post/cote-divoire/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2014 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gongchm.github.io/post/cote-divoire/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;5月16日中午，首届非洲智能电网论坛主要议程已经结束，主办方到餐厅找到了中国国家电网公司代表团，提出希望邀请SGCC在下午的闭幕式上致辞。因几位领导的行程已定，我被指派在下午的闭幕式上代表国网致辞。公司副总工程师王益民先生对如何致辞作了认真细致的交待，中午花一个多小时完成致辞初稿，驻非办领导任远帮助进行了修改。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fri, May 16, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abidjan, Cote d’ivoire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good afternoon, Dear&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Adama Toungara, Minister of Oil and Energy,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Dominique Kakou, Director General of CIE,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Frans Vreeswijk, Secretary Generalof IEC,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Claude Kutwa, AFSEC President,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good afternoon, Ladies and Gentlemen,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On behalf of the State Grid Corporation of China, on behalf of Madem Chen Yueming, the Executive Vice President of SGCC and the head of SGCC delegation, I’d first express the warmest congratulations on the success of the first Africa Smart Grid Forum. During this forum, SGCC shared the ideas, practice and achievements on the design and implementation of the smart grid in China. Experts from different countries and organizations gave us positive feedback and valuable comments and also their specific ideas and experience sharing on this forum are quite helpful to us. We have benefited a lot from the forum and we regard this forum as a high-level and valuable event for the electricity professions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The practice of smart grid started in China from only several years ago, but the rapid and significant progress has been achieved. One of the most favorable factors for the progress is that China is a developing country and the grid there is also under developing. We could systematically plan the development of smart grid without too many constraints of traditional ways. The second favorable factor is that the power system of State Grid is quite large. We could test different ideas in different areas at the same time and then apply the successful results to the whole grid later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Africa is the land of hope. Many Africa countries and grids are rapidly developing and facing many challenges as China once faced. When facing the future progress, Africa colleagues are wisely considering the journey of smart grid. It will definitely be a hopeful while challenging journey. SGCC are willing to share our experience continuously, deal with the challenges together and explore the new innovative solutions bravely. We have established our Africa office based in South Africa, aiming to enhance the exchange and cooperation in Africa. Let’s join our hands for wider and deeper cooperation in the development of smart grid in Africa and contribute the most for the takeoff of Africa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Congratulate the success of the forum again. Welcome you to come to China and visit SGCC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>通过了IEEE Computer Society的CSDP认证</title>
      <link>https://gongchm.github.io/post/csdp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gongchm.github.io/post/csdp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;5月出版的IEEE Computer杂志在Computer Society Connection专栏公布了最新通过CSDP认证的名单，很荣幸我名列其中，自己努力尝试的目标达成了。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;自己的专业教育背景和从事的工作是电气工程，但是提供的产品和服务都是软件方面的，尽管平时不断在学习软件方面的知识，但是一直觉得缺少系统的训练和检验。正好看到IEEE计算机协会开展软件工程的认证，决定参照这一认证的要求系统地学习软件工程的理论，学完了以后报名参加了IEEE的考试。考试时又有机会回了趟南大母校，考试的方式是和外语考试类似的机考，英文试卷。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;考试后就等着结果，最终等到了通过的消息，对自己来说，也更有信心去从事软件领域的工作。我也会向其他同事朋友推荐这一认证考试。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;一起公布通过这批认证的美国人有87位，中国人有3位，印度人有7位，其他国家的有21位。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CSDP认证借鉴了PMP认证的方式，发布了Software Engineering Body of Knowledge(SWBOK)，以此知识体系作为认证的基础。SWBOK涵盖软件需求、软件设计、软件构造、软件测试、软件维护、软件配置管理、软件工程管理、软件工程过程、软件工程工具和方法、软件质量共十个知识领域，其中通过CSDP认证可被认为达到proficiency of standard software development practices的程度。稍低一个级别的认证是CSDA。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Computer Society Connection的原文可以从&lt;a href=&#34;http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?tp=&amp;amp;arnumber=5472895&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;IEEE Xplore&lt;/a&gt;上下载到。&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
